A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12 FA284
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12
1930-1952
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
Harkness, Charles W.
Harkness, Mary Emma Stillman
Harkness, Edward Stephen
Harkness, Anna M. Richardson
FA284
22 Cubic Feet 50 boxes
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for scholarly research, except where particular restrictions are noted.
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Arrangement note
This series is arranged in 3 subseries:
Subseries 1 General Files
Subseries 2 State Files
Subseries 3 Public Health Fellowships
The fellowship files contained in this series are arranged alphabetically, first by state and then by last name of recipient.
Biographical/Historical note
The Commonwealth Fund was established in 1918 with an endowment of $10 million from Mrs. Stephen V. Harkness for "benevolent, religious, educational and like purposes." The early grants supported a variety of programs while generally promoting welfare, especially child welfare. Several grants were made in the field of medical research, but the Board of Directors decided in 1920 that this field was already sufficiently supported by other philanthropic organizations.
Despite this decision, by the mid-1920s the chief interest of the Fund had become public health, including mental hygiene, community health, rural hospitals, medical research, and medical education. Other grant areas included war relief, educational and legal research, child welfare, and international medical fellowships.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IX; IV 4B 4
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Scope and Contents note
The Commonwealth Fund announced in late 1929 a new project that began operation on January 1, 1930, and promoted rural health and medical service in the United States. The new program, instead of emphasizing child care, comprised all health services in rural communities. Initially the project was limited to two states, Tennessee (1930-1945) and Massachusetts (1930-1945), and to two counties or districts in each state. Later the program was also active in Mississippi (1931-1947), Oklahoma (1938-1949), Alabama (1938-1942), Arkansas (1945-1947), California, Florida (1945-1947), Kentucky (1945-1947), Louisiana (1946), Maine, New Jersey, Ohio, Virginia, and Washington. Dr. William J. French, the first director of the CF's child-health demonstration in Fargo, North Dakota, and former head of the CF's Austrian Program, was named director. French resigned his post on April 4, 1931, and on May 15, 1931, Clarence L. Scamman became the new director of the Division.
The goals set forth were to create field units to promote rural health service and develop well-rounded health services. The work was conducted with the cooperation of the states' health departments. The project also included the establishment of scholarships for graduate study by rural physicians and for nurses and teachers who wished to study methods of health education, and scholarships or loan funds for medical students who would undertake rural practice. The fellowship files contained in this series cover the years 1931 to 1951. A complete alphabetical card file index to the fellowships is available. The use of files may be restricted if they contain information of a personal or sensitive nature.
Other Finding Aids
Other available finding aids describing the Commonwealth Fund records include:
FA247 Commonwealth Fund Harkness House drawings
FA276 Commonwealth Fund records, Annual Reports, SG 1, Series 4
FA277 Commonwealth Fund records, Archives/Library, SG 1, Series 5
FA278 Commonwealth Fund records, Austrian Program, SG 1, Series 6
FA279 Commonwealth Fund records, Board of Directors, SG 1, Series 7
FA280 Commonwealth Fund records, Capital Grants, SG 1, Series 8
FA281 Commonwealth Fund records, Child Health Demonstrations, SG 1, Series 9
FA282 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Community Clinics, SG 1, Series 10
FA283 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Health Studies, SG 1, Series 11
FA284 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12
FA285 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Publications, SG 1, Series 13
FA286 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Rural Hospitals, SG 1, Series 14
FA287 Commonwealth Fund records, Educational Research, SG 1, Series 15
FA288 Commonwealth Fund records, English Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 16
FA289 Commonwealth Fund records, Finance Committee, SG 1, Series 17
FA290 Commonwealth Fund records, Grants, SG 1, Series 18
FA291 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Family, SG 1, Series 19
FA292 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, SG 1, Series 20
FA428 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, Fellows Reports, SG 1, Series 20A
FA293 Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21
FA294 Commonwealth Fund records, Interface Program, SG 1, Series 22
FA295 Commonwealth Fund records, Legal Research Program, SG 1, Series 23
FA296 Commonwealth Fund records, Living at Home Program, SG 1, Series 24
FA297 Commonwealth Fund records, Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 25
FA298 Commonwealth Fund records, Miscellaneous - unprocessed
FA299 Commonwealth Fund records, Personnel - unprocessed
FA300 Commonwealth Fund records, Pilgrim Trust, SG 1, Series 28
FA301 Commonwealth Fund records, Program for the Prevention of Delinquency, SG 1, Series 29
FA302 Commonwealth Fund records, Reference Files, SG 1, Series 30
FA303 Commonwealth Fund records, Reports of the General Director, SG 1, Series 31
FA304 Commonwealth Fund records, Treasurer, SG 1, Series 32
FA305 Commonwealth Fund records, Turndown Lists, SG 1, Series 33 - unprocessed
FA306 Commonwealth Fund records, Vertical File (R. Fitz), SG 1, Series 34 - unprocessed
FA307 Commonwealth Fund records, Visual Materials, SG 1, Series 35
FA389 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Historical Files, SG 1, Series 1
FA390 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Officers Files, SG 1, Series 2
FA429 Commonwealth Fund records, President, Margaret E. Mahoney, SG 2, Series 1
FA430 Commonwealth Fund records, Book Program, SG 2, Series 2
Medical research; Medicine, Rural; Legal research; Medical education; Medicine -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Mental health; War relief; New York (State); Public health; Public welfare; United States; Child welfare; Child psychology; Child mental health; New York (N.Y.); Legal issues; Law; Hygiene; Education, Rural; Harvard University; Social Science Research Council; Yale University; Phillips Exeter Academy; Columbia University
- General Files, 1
  Arrangement note
  This subseries is divided into 5 parts:
  Part 1 American Public Health Association
  Part 2 Program Files
  Part 3 Miscellaneous Projects and Grants
  Part 4 Special Studies
  Part 5 United States Public Health Service Files
  - American Public Health Association, 1
    - Accreditation of Schools of Public Health - Correspondence and Reports, April 24, 1945-April 20, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Accreditation of Schools of Public Health - Correspondence and Reports, April 24, 1945-April 20, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - State Health Studies - Correspondence and Reports, October 21, 1947-January 29, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - State Health Studies - Correspondence and Reports, October 21, 1947-January 29, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Subcommittee on Grading - Correspondence and Reports, April 14, 1948-May 9, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Subcommittee on Opportunities in Statistical Work - Correspondence, January 9, 1947-July 29, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Subcommittee on State and Local Health Administration - Correspondence, Minutes and Reports, November 29, 1929 to September 1, 1939; January 2, 1945 to November 16, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Subcommittee on State and Local Health Administration - Correspondence, Minutes and Reports, November 29, 1929 to September 1, 1939; January 2, 1945 to November 16, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Program Files, 2
    - Annual Reports, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Annual Reports, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Annual Reports, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Annual Reports, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Annual Reports, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Annual Reports, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Annual Reports, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Annual Reports, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-1948 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Athens, Georgia) - General Correspondence, August 28, 1929-August 23, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Fargo, North Dakota) - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, January 1, 1927-July 2, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Fargo, North Dakota) - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, January 1, 1927-July 2, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Fargo, North Dakota) - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, January 1, 1927-July 2, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Marion County, Oregon) - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, January 1, 1926-June 30, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Marion County, Oregon) - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, August 23, 1928-January 28, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Marion County, Oregon) - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, August 23, 1928-January 28, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Marion County, Oregon) - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, August 23, 1928-January 28, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Marion County, Oregon) - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, August 23, 1928-January 28, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Marion County, Oregon) - Correspondence, Memoranda and Reports, August 23, 1928-January 28, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Annual Report, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Charter and Program Development, April 22, 1930-August 11, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Correspondence and Memoranda, June 25, 1929-October 26, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Correspondence and Memoranda, June 25, 1929-October 26, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Correspondence and Memoranda, June 25, 1929-October 26, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Correspondence and Memoranda, June 25, 1929-October 26, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Report of Public Health Activities, 1924-1933 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Statistical Summary of Public Health Activities, 1921-1950 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Statistical Summary of Public Health Activities, 1921-1950 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Study of Public Health Activities, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Summary of Public Health Activities, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Surveys of Public Health Activities, 1923-1928 and 1923-1929; 1927 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Surveys of Public Health Activities, 1923-1928 and 1923-1929; 1927 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Surveys of Public Health Activities, 1932 and 1934; 1942 and 1944 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Child Health Demonstration (Rutherford County, Tennessee) - Surveys of Public Health Activities, 1932 and 1934; 1942 and 1944 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Correspondence, October 30, 1930-October 8, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, October 30, 1930-October 8, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence, October 30, 1930-October 8, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Correspondence, October 30, 1930-October 8, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence, October 30, 1930-October 8, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Correspondence, October 30, 1930-October 8, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Correspondence, October 30, 1930-October 8, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Field Reports, January 1933 to October 1937; November 1943 to December 1948 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Field Reports, January 1933 to October 1937; November 1943 to December 1948 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Memoranda - Sheehan, September 8, 1947-June 21, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Memoranda - Sheehan, September 8, 1947-June 21, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Memoranda - Smith, December 18, 1930-December 5, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Memoranda - Smith, December 18, 1930-December 5, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Memoranda - Smith, December 18, 1930-December 5, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Memoranda - Smith, December 18, 1930-December 5, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Memoranda - Smith, December 18, 1930-December 5, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Memoranda - Smith, January 25, 1940-August 20, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Memoranda - Smith, January 25, 1940-August 20, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Memoranda - Smith, January 25, 1940-August 20, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Memoranda - Smith, January 25, 1940-August 20, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Memoranda and Reports, June 1, 1930-March 31, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Memoranda and Reports, June 1, 1930-March 31, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Memoranda and Reports, June 1, 1930-March 31, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Memoranda and Reports, June 1, 1930-March 31, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Memoranda and Reports, June 1, 1930-March 31, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Memoranda and Reports, June 1, 1930-March 31, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Memoranda and Reports, June 1, 1930-March 31, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Program Budgets and Memoranda, January 1, 1948-June 30, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Program Budgets and Memoranda, January 1, 1948-June 30, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Program Outline and Memoranda, January 1, 1928-June 30, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - Roster - Advisory Committee on Public Health, 1930-1946 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - Miscellaneous Projects and Grants, 3
    - Albany Medical College - Correspondence and Memoranda, November 23, 1948-November 4, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - Bingham Fund Associates - General Files, October 22, 1931-November 13, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - Columbia University School of Public Health - Memoranda and Correspondence, July 9, 1945-December 16, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - Columbia University School of Public Health - Memoranda and Correspondence, July 9, 1945-December 16, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - Conference of Deans of Schools of Public Health - Correspondence, November 12, 1948-October 19, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - Health Education - University of Tennessee - Report, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Health Education - University of Tennessee - Report, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - Health Education - University of Tennessee - Seminar Material, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - Health Education - University of Tennessee - Seminar Material, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Mental Health Institute - Conference Material, April 26, 1949-May 7, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Mental Health Institute - Correspondence and Memoranda, November 5, 1948-June 23, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - Mental Health Institute - Correspondence and Memoranda, November 5, 1948-June 23, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - Mental Health Institute - Correspondence and Memoranda, November 5, 1948-June 23, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - Mental Health Institute - Correspondence and Memoranda, November 5, 1948-June 23, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - Mental Health Institute - Correspondence and Memoranda, November 5, 1948-June 23, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - Undergraduate Fellowship Program - Correspondence and Memoranda, September 22, 1939-June 17, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 99)
    - Undergraduate Fellowship Program - Correspondence and Memoranda, September 22, 1939-June 17, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - University of Michigan School of Public Health - Correspondence, April 5, 1950-May 5, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - University of North Carolina - Correspondence and Program Outline, September 8, 1949-April 14, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - University of North Carolina - Correspondence and Program Outline, September 8, 1949-April 14, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 103)
    - University of Toronto - Correspondence and Memoranda, March 23, 1948-November 30, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 104)
    - Vanderbilt University Medical School Scholarships and Internships - Correspondence and Reports, January 8, 1932-December 27, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 105)
    - Vanderbilt University Medical School Scholarships and Internships - Correspondence and Reports, January 8, 1932-December 27, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 106)
    - Vanderbilt University Medical School Scholarships and Internships - Correspondence and Reports, January 8, 1932-December 27, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 107)
    - Vanderbilt University Medical School Scholarships and Internships - Correspondence and Reports, January 8, 1932-December 27, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 108)
    - Yale University - Correspondence and Reports, October 1, 1948-January 13, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 109)
  - Special Studies, 4
    - Blood Study (Pike County Mississippi) - Memoranda and Reports, April 28, 1936-September 30, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 110)
    - Conference of State and Provincial Health Authorities (Committee on Records) - Memoranda and Correspondence, April 9, 1936-June 14, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 111)
    - Conference of State and Provincial Health Authorities (Committee on Records) - Report, February-July 1941 (Box 7, Folder 112)
    - Conference of State and Provincial Health Authorities (Committee on Records) - Report, July 2, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 113)
    - Field Unit Study (Tennessee) - Memoranda and Reports, January 26, 1937-June 24, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - Maternity Study (County Health Departments) - Reports and Correspondence, August 25, 1944-August 1, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 115)
    - Maternity Study (County Health Departments) - Reports and Correspondence, August 25, 1944-August 1, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 116)
    - Maternity Study (Gibson County Tennessee) - Correspondence and Reports, September 19, 1933-December 29, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 117)
    - Maternity Study (Gibson County Tennessee) - Correspondence and Reports, September 19, 1933-December 29, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 118)
    - Maternity Study (Gibson County Tennessee) - Correspondence and Reports, September 19, 1933-December 29, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 119)
    - Maternity Study (Gibson County Tennessee) - Correspondence and Reports, September 19, 1933-December 29, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 120)
    - Maternity Study (Jones County Mississippi) - Correspondence and Reports, June 25, 1940-May 12, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 121)
    - Maternity Study (Pike County Mississippi) - Correspondence and Memoranda, December 2, 1935-September 18, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 122)
    - Maternity Study (Pike County Mississippi) - Reports, 1937-1945 (Box 8, Folder 123)
    - New York City Health Department Records - Reports, January 26, 1948-April 6, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - Nursing Study (Southern Berkshire Health District, Massachusetts) - Memoranda and Reports, November 28, 1933-November 18, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 125)
    - Nursing Study (Southern Berkshire Health District, Massachusetts) - Memoranda and Reports, November 28, 1933-November 18, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 126)
    - Record Unit and Institute - Correspondence and Memoranda, March 8, 1935-December 21, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 127)
    - Rutherford County Tennessee - Statistical Studies, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 128)
    - Rutherford County Tennessee - Statistical Studies, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 129)
    - Rutherford County Tennessee - Study on Health Services for Mothers and Young Children in Rural Areas, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - School Health Services (Tennessee) - Correspondence Reports and Memoranda, October 6, 1936-December 3, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - School Health Services (Tennessee) - Correspondence Reports and Memoranda, October 6, 1936-December 3, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 132)
    - School Health Services (Tennessee) - Correspondence Reports and Memoranda, October 6, 1936-December 3, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 133)
    - Syphilis Study (Gibson County Tennessee) - Memoranda and Reports, June 11, 1935-January 14, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - Syphilis Study (Gibson County Tennessee) - Memoranda and Reports, June 11, 1935-January 14, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 135)
    - Syphilis Study (Gibson County Tennessee) - Memoranda and Reports, June 11, 1935-January 14, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 136)
    - Syphilis Study (Tennessee and Mississippi) - Memoranda and Reports, January 6, 1943-December 5, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 137)
    - Tuberculosis Studies (Oklahoma and Mississippi) - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, February 26, 1946-May 17, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 138)
    - Tuberculosis Studies (Oklahoma and Mississippi) - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, February 26, 1946-May 17, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 139)
    - Tuberculosis Studies (Oklahoma and Mississippi) - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, February 26, 1946-May 17, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 140)
    - Tuberculosis Studies (Oklahoma and Mississippi) - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, February 26, 1946-May 17, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 141)
    - Tuberculosis Studies (Oklahoma and Mississippi) - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, February 26, 1946-May 17, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 142)
    - Tuberculosis Studies (Oklahoma and Mississippi) - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, February 26, 1946-May 17, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 143)
    - Typhoid Fever Study (Rutherford County Mississippi) - Correspondence and Reports, February 1, 1932-October 29, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 144)
  - United States Public Health Service Files, 5
    - Federal Security Agency - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, February 11, 1948-May 14, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 145)
    - Federal Security Agency - Correspondence Memoranda and Reports, February 11, 1948-May 14, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 146)
    - General Correspondence and Memoranda, April 25, 1945-December 20, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 147)
- State Files, 2
  - Alabama - Annual Reports, 1938-1941 (Box 10, Folder 148)
  - Alabama - Annual Reports, 1938-1941 (Box 10, Folder 149)
  - Alabama - Annual Reports, 1938-1941 (Box 10, Folder 150)